A Whole New Breed of Heroes.
TMNT is a adventure, animation, comedy film directed by Kevin Munroe.
After the defeat of their old arch nemesis, The Shredder,
the Turtles have grown apart as a family.
Struggling to keep them together, their rat sensei, Splinter, becomes
worried when strange things begin to brew in New York City.
Leonardo (voice), played by James Arnold Taylor.
Donatello / Additional Voices (voice), played by Mitchell Whitfield.
Raphael / Nightwatcher (voice), played by Nolan North.
Michelangelo (voice), played by Mikey Kelley.
April O'Neil (voice), played by Sarah Michelle Gellar.
Casey Jones (voice), played by Chris Evans.
TMNT (abbreviated from Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles) is a 2007 animated superhero film written and directed by Kevin
Munroe in his feature directorial debut and based on the characters created by Peter Laird and Kevin Eastman.
The first animated film in the franchise, it features the voices of Chris Evans, Sarah Michelle Gellar,
Mako, Kevin Smith, Patrick Stewart, and Ziyi Zhang with narration by Laurence Fishburne.
In the film, after having grown apart following the final defeat of their arch-enemy, the Shredder, the four Turtles — Leonardo, Raphael, Donatello, and Michelangelo (voiced respectively
by James Arnold Taylor, Nolan North, Mitchell Whitfield, and Mikey Kelley) — are set to reunite and overcome their faults to save the world from evil ancient creatures.
Development and pre-production for TMNT began in June 2005 at Imagi's Los Angeles facility and
the animation was produced in Hong Kong, followed by post-production in Hollywood.
Munroe chose to produce the film in CGI animation as opposed to live-action like the prior Turtles
films, in an effort to make it easier for audiences to suspend their disbelief.
When writing the film, Munroe wanted to divert away from the lighthearted elements of the
franchise and put a heavier emphasis on the darker tone of the original comics.
The animators that worked on the fight sequences were
inspired by Hong Kong action films.
TMNT premiered at the Grauman's Chinese Theatre in Los Angeles on March 17, 2007, and was
released theatrically in the United States on March 23, by Warner Bros.
Pictures, it was released in Hong Kong on March 29 by Golden Scene, and
internationally distributed by The Weinstein Company.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, but was a small commercial success,
grossing $95.6 million worldwide against a $34 million production budget.
Planned sequels were cancelled after Nickelodeon acquired the franchise in
2009, rebooting the film series with a live-action film in 2014.
The film explores themes of new york city, journalist,
martial arts, sibling relationship, skateboarding.
The tone is lighthearted.